Speaker 1
Today I invite you to prepare together a wonderful orache soup recipe, just like in
Oltenia. It's very tasty, aromatic, with plenty of vegetables and lots of
greens. It's perfect after a period when we ate far too much meat.
Let's prepare it together. For the ingredients, we will need
6 bunches of orache, 2 bunches of sorrel, 2 onions finely chopped
half a liter of borscht, 2 red peppers cut into
cubes, a bunch of lovage, two carrots, a quarter of
celery root, 4–5 tablespoons of oil, and a pinch of salt. This
sorrel soup recipe is very easy and very tasty. I'll start
with the oil that I'll put in a pot, and now
Speaker 1
I'll let it heat up. When the oil is hot, I'll add
the onion. The bell pepper.
The celery and the carrot. I'll season with a little
salt. And I'll cook the vegetables until they soften, about 5
Speaker 1
minutes. Make sure not to fry them, but just sauté them enough for them to release their
juices. When the vegetables have softened and look like this
Speaker 1
they should look. We can
add about three liters of water over them. We cook
the vegetables for about 10–15 minutes or until they are
almost done. At this point, you can also add a little rice
or potatoes while the vegetables are cooking. I can take care of the greens and
I'll start with the orache. Here I have some beautiful red orache,
Speaker 1
which I'll chop. As you could
see, I've also kept a bit of the stem because it's very healthy.
Optionally, you can add some sorrel. I like to add it because I have it in
Speaker 1
my garden and because it's green and, of course, because it's just as
healthy. Sorrel has a sour taste and goes
Speaker 1
very well in this soup.
The vegetables have boiled, so I can add the sorrel and orache mixture.
Speaker 1
And I’ll let the soup boil for another 5 minutes.
After those 5 minutes have passed, I will add the borscht that I boiled earlier.
And I'll let it come to a few more boils.
Speaker 1
At this point, taste the soup and add more salt if needed.
After the soup has come to a few more boils, I can turn off the heat and
add the chopped lovage. Of course, you can also add parsley and even
Speaker 1
a little green onion. I’ll stir for the last time.
And Oltenian orache soup is ready. Exactly how my
grandmother used to make it. My dears, this is my orache soup recipe
how I used to eat it in childhood. My grandmother made it very often in spring
and it was absolutely delicious. You can also add,
for example, rice or potatoes, but I like it plain for an extra
flavor. You can serve it with a bit of sour cream or even some horseradish. This
soup is wonderful in spring, has lots of vegetables, is very healthy
and it's perfect after a period when I ate a lot of meat, as many of us did at Easter,
I sincerely hope you try the recipe yourselves and that you enjoy it.
Goodbye!